Had taken health insurance for peace of mind, but at the time of claim, when the hospital bill
came, there were many excuses like room rent, copay payment etc. In true sense,
it is only at the time of claim that policy holders come to know
what things are actually covered in their policy. In today's video, we
are going to understand the Aditya Birla Active One Max Plan. Along with its basic coverage benefits, we will also
understand the USPC i.e. the features that make this plan. What makes Super Reload very special
is the unlimited restoration benefit of Aditya Birla Active One Plan. How
will it work and how can you avail its benefits? We will also know
what is Super Credit benefit and how you can use it.
Along with knowing all the benefits and coverages, we will also understand the pricing of this plan so that
we can also check the affordability of this plan and Aditya Birla Activ Max and Max Plus.
There is not much difference in the plan , there is a difference of only two features, so
you will know that difference in today's video, so today's video
is going to give you complete clarity of this plan, that too in a completely transparent and unbiased manner, so
without any delay, let's start this video immediately. First of all, let
us understand some special features of Aditya Birla1 Max Plan. The first USP of this plan is that in it
you will get the benefits of contracting diseases like HIV or sexually transmitted diseases. Most plans will give you this coverage,
but its coverage
has been mentioned in this plan, which is a positive point. Not only this,
you also get coverage for mental illness in this plan, such as if there is hospitalization due to anxiety and depression,
which is a very common problem today, then you
will get that coverage in this plan. This coverage is also mentioned in the policy terms,
although the IRDA guidelines say that all Health insurance companies
should provide this coverage. Apart from this, you get the feature of Claim Protect here which
is their consumable benefit. Now what is special in this, it is available in most of the plans,
the special thing is that under this Claim Protect feature, you
get coverage of non-medical items of all four lists of Ener One, that too through the Super Reload benefit within the standard plan,
you can avail the benefit of unlimited times restoration.
For details and terms and conditions, wait till the section on Coverage and Benefits,
there we will discuss them in detail and Super Credit is also
a very special feature under which you can collect cumulative bonus
up to five times of your basic sum insured, that too irrespective of claim and the final
USP that I have seen in this plan is Health Returns. Health Returns
say that you will get rewards equal to your annual premium.
You can get points if you keep your lifestyle active, then for this
you will have to maintain the average of your monthly and yearly step count, then
you can save up to 100% of your renewal premium under this plan, so let us first
understand the eligibility conditions for taking this plan. If we talk about adults,
then the minimum entry age is 18 years and there is no capping on the maximum age.
If we talk about dependent child then minimum entry age is 91 days and maximum
age is 25 years. Policy type: You can take both individual and family floater.
If we talk about tenure, then you also get the option of long term policy of 1 year, 2 years and three years
under this plan. The definition of family is given here: two
adults and four dependents. In most of the child plans, you
get the option of two or three dependent children, but within this plan,
you can add four dependent children with you in a family floater option. How will the premium be, it
will be zone based. There is no zone based copayment, that is, you
can go to another zone and get treatment, but you will have to take the policy
according to your residing address, i.e. the zone at which you are living. Three What are the zones, these are currently
visible to you on the screen. You
can verify the zone of your city or state from here. Many times this question comes that sir, in these companies,
the premium in the plans is age banded or not. Age banded premium means that
the premium of your policy will be revised with your age, but there will not be this revision in age every year.
An age band is made, mostly it is of 5 years, so only after that this age
revision is done. If it is so, the premium will remain banded under this plan also.
The options of sum insured are also quite flexible which is currently visible to you on the screen. Minimum sum
Insured is of ₹ 2 lakh and maximum you can cover your family up to ₹ crore of basic
sum insured. Now let's talk about some features of coverage and benefits. So the first point
we will discuss here is Room Rent Limit. There
is no capping of room rent in both the variants of Aitya Birla Activ Max and Max Plus. Although you can modify it,
but within the standard plan, you can choose any room during the treatment. Next
coverage is day care treatment i.e. those treatments for which you
do not need to be admitted for the whole day for 24 hours, day care treatments which
are listed on the website of the insurance company will also be covered up to the sum insured. You can also claim the expenses of road ambulance
in this. Any hospitalization in which
the insurance company accepts your claim and the ambulance is used for that treatment.
If any expenses have been incurred for transporting or bringing the patient, then you
can also claim that expense under this policy and if we talk about modern treatments, then this
is a very important coverage and these days it is often asked about whether there
is any supplement or not, then the 12 modern treatments listed under this plan are
covered up to some insured, there is no supplement and apart from these, if
any modern treatment is a part of the treatment then You can claim that too, it
is not so, these are the listed 12 modern treatments that can be used, these 12
have been mentioned by IRDA, apart from these, if any modern treatment
is a part of your treatment and it is necessary to use it on the doctor's recommendation, then you
can also claim HIV AIDS or any sexually transmitted disease which
comes within the coverage guidelines of the policy, that is also covered up to. Sum insured and apart from this,
any inpatient hospitalization related to mental illness will also be covered up to sum
insured. Obesity treatment i.e. the surgery done for obesity, basically
bariatric surgery, will also be covered by this plan. However, it is included in the exclusions, but if
the BAMI norms mentioned are very extreme or there are other conditions,
then if any treatment qualifies to get its coverage. Then
you can also take its coverage under this plan and there is no supplement on it. It is
also covered up to some insure. If we talk about pre and post hospitalization
expenses, then 90 days of prehospitalization and 180 days
of post hospitalization expenses related to any treatment will be covered in this plan and these expenses
will include doctor consultation charges. Medicines and Diagnostic Tests also
related to this specific treatment for which you have claimed Earlier Claim
Protect benefit is a standard feature of this plan under which
you can cover non-medical items from all four lists in the annexure. Domicile treatment, home care
treatment and all the treatments related to AYUSH are covered up to sum
insured for AYUSH if you are on any AYUSH. In a day care center or an AYUSH certified
facility, you get treatment in a hospital.
Only if there is inpatient hospitalization, it will be covered. For domicory treatment, this treatment
is on the recommendation of a doctor and it is taken due to some compulsion, that is, the patient is not in a condition that you
can take them to the hospital or if there are no beds available in the hospital where the treatment is to be done,
then it can be taken at home and one special thing is required. Keep
in mind that in most of the cases, sickness and illness are excluded under
domiciliary treatment. This is not the case with home care treatment. You can
take treatment at home from a certified home care service provider after taking approval from the insurance company.
Any compulsion condition that is there is not applicable here, you
can take it as per your wish but after taking approval from the insurance company,
if you talk to This claim of organ donor is quite rare but when it comes,
its expenses are very high, so this is also the expense which this plan will cover. These expenses
can be covered. Up to sum insured. There is no supplement but there
are some exclusions which are visible to you right now on the screen like pre and post
oscillation expenses of the donor, expense of transporting or preserving the organ or
apart from this there are some other expenses which are This plan will not cover those which are excluded,
so it is very important to understand them. You can also get the annual health checkup done under this plan.
You will be able to get these listed tests done which you are currently seeing on the screen
and you will have to get them done on cashless basis only, that is,
the labs of Aditya Birla Health Insurance which are certified, that is, the network labs which are network facilities.
Now let's talk about the Super Reload
benefit, which is the refill i.e. restoration benefit of this plan. If
during any treatment, your sum insured or any cumulative bonus like super
credit gets exhausted, then you can use the super reload benefit for the same treatment.
If this amount falls short in the treatment, then super reload up to basic sum
insured will refill your amount by recharging. Will give the most special conditional
condition that you have to see in it is that
you will not be able to use the super reload benefit for the first claim within the life time of your policy. Suppose
I have a policy running for 5 years, I have not taken any claim in it and
suddenly a claim comes which is a big claim. If this is the first claim then I will not be able to use the super
reload benefit for subsequent claims after one claim.
During the whole life time of the policy I can use this Super Reload
benefit up to the Basic Sum Insured Along with this, the next very important feature
that comes is Super Credit. Super Credit is the cumulative bonus of this plan or
an extended version of the cumulative bonus in which if you take any claim in the whole year or not,
irrespective of the claim, you will get 100% sum insured of your basic sum insured
on every renewal. And the maximum limit for that number of times of sum
insured is five times i.e. if there is a policy of ₹ 1 lakh then you
can collect super credit of ₹ lakh. You
will continue to get this 100% of basic sum insured on renewal every year and if any claim comes,
what will be the sequence of using the sum insured i.e. which money will be used first. It is also important to know that first of all
you will use the basic sum insured and then any bonus like super.
If there is credit, then its money will be utilized. Third comes is Super Reload, that is, the
refill benefit that I told, its money will be utilized. And final sum ensure that
you can utilize in this sequence is Cancer Booster Cover. What is this, I
will explain to you in the advanced section but the last one which will come in the sequence is Cancer
Booster Cover, so in this sequence only, you can utilize your sum insured.
Health Assessment is a very important part of this plan. This is a special feature and is not a health assessment. This health
assessment is linked to the health return, that is, which can save you premium on your renewal.
This health assessment is also linked to the same. You can get the health assessment done in two ways,
online and offline. What is the online method? You will directly scan your face in Aditya Birla's
app, then on the basis of this can you will get a healthy heart
score, that is, how healthy is your heart. Based on this face can,
according to it, you will get a score. You will get it and accordingly you will be assigned a category.
The better this category is, that is, the more healthy you are, the
more discount you will get on the basis of step count and the discount you will get will be
in the form of health returns. So what are the health returns? Whatever your daily step
count is, an average will be calculated on your monthly basis and an average
will be calculated on annual basis if you qualify this step count in both the averages. If you have a plan
then you get up to 100% off renewal premium , you get a discount equal to
the renewal amount you have to pay. This is a kind of wellness benefit, but
what is different from other plans is that in other plans you get a discount of up to 10%, 20%, 30%
, but all the variants of this plan, Aditya Birla Active One, almost offer you
up to 100% off renewal premium. You can save, if not the full 100%,
30% or 40% of your renewal premium is also absorbed, so it is not a bad deal, you can do this
and the second benefit is that along with this, you will also remain fit because you are actively
completing your step count. Now friends, the next two features which I
am going to tell you right now, these are within the Aditya Birla Active One Max variant, so you
will get an add on i.e. extra money for these. But if you
choose the Max Plus variant, then you
will get these two features as standard inbuilt in that plan. There
is a difference of only these two features within the Max and Max Plus variants, so let us understand them. Let us know what are these features. The first feature
is the durable equipment cover which
is related to some treatment. This list is visible to you on the screen right now and these doctors recommend
the treatment. You have to buy or rent them within the next 30 days.
If the doctor recommends you, then you
can take its compensation under this plan. What is the amount of compensation? Maximum up to ₹ 5 lakh cumulative.
You can claim this together. Keep in mind that in the Max variant, this is as an add on,
you will have to take it. This is a standard feature in the Max Plus variant. The second
feature, friends, is Advanced Health Checkups. Under this feature, you
get two extra tests, in which the first test is That is Computed
Tomography Angiography or you can also say Angiography directly
and the second test is Positron Emission Tomography i.e. PET Scan.
You can get both these tests done in your standard plan if you have Max
Plus variant and if you take Max variant then you will have to take an add on.
This facility is available only on cashless basis and there is
initial waiting period to get these tests done. The period is that of 90 days. Now friends, let us
understand the add ons of Aitya Birla Activ 1 Max and Max Plus variants, that is, those features which you
can optionally add in your plan and increase your coverage.
Why is it important to understand these features because they can completely change your coverage, so the first add on here
is the specific disease to modify the waiting period.
Those listed elements are minor surgeries, medical
procedures that will be covered after 24 months but if you
take this add on then you can reduce that waiting period time up to 12 months. Similarly,
if there is any pre-existing disease which the policy holder is suffering from before taking the policy,
then its waiting period is 36 months and if you declare After getting to know about
the insurance company, they give you the policy only then if she is eligible for PED then its
waiting period to cover the treatment is 36 months. There is a waiting period of 3 years. You
can reduce it from three to 2 years i.e. from 3 years to 2 years and also from 2 years to one year.
The shorter the waiting period, the
more money you will get for this. Add on will have to be paid. There is no capping on room rent in this standard plan,
but if you want capping on room rent,
your premium will be slightly less than this, then you
can choose both the options of single private AC room or twin sharing. Not only this, you
can also choose the option of per claim deductible to reduce your premium. ₹ 1,000 and ₹ 25,000 are
the two options given by the company in the policy. Whenever the claim comes, whatever option you choose,
you will have to pay this amount from your own pocket, after that the coverage of the policy
will start. The insurance company will give you the claim and I am talking about any approved claim.
Apart from this, there is a list of preferred provider network i.e.
on the website of Aditya Birla Health Insurance, you will get a list of networks. List of preferred
provider network. These are some special hospitals. If you take this add on
then If you take treatment in these hospitals, you will get 100% claim, but
why would you do this, why would you restrict your choice because in
return the insurance company will give you a discount of 10%, I think this
should be avoided, it should not be taken because a person may have to take treatment anywhere,
so do not choose such add ons, but still the company has
given you the option. This health insurance policy of yours covers the treatment of critical illness. But if
you want to take the add on of Critical Illness separately, so that if any of the listed serious
diseases is diagnosed, the insurance company will give you a sum amount, then
you can choose this add on also. Here, Sum Insured,
the options you are currently seeing on the screen are 10 Lakh, 15 Lakh, 20 Lakh and 25 Lakh and on taking this add on,
the initial waiting period which will be there will be off. 60 days:
You cannot make this claim within the first two months of taking the policy
and once the claim is filed , after the diagnosis, a survival period of 15 days is necessary, that is, it
is necessary for the patient to remain alive. Similarly, you
can also take personal accidental coverage for lumpsum compensation under which, if an
adult policy holder dies due to an accident or any permanent If there is total disability or permanent
partial disability, then the company will give sum benefit in that case. For this,
the options of sum insured are 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh and 50 lakh is the maximum
coverage amount. It is a very important add on for chronic care. The medical
conditions listed in this which you are currently seeing on the screen are Diabetes, Hypertension, Asthma.
Hyperlipidemia COPD Obesity and Coronary Artery Disease These seven medical
conditions will be covered from the first day. If you take this add on, then no
waiting period will be applicable on them.
For the detailed terms and conditions of its coverage, you can refer to the policy wordings given in the description of this video
and if any of these seven conditions listed is PED. So
his waiting period will end and if someone
is diagnosed for the first time after taking this policy, it will be covered from the first day. If you take this add on Chronic Care,
along with this there is also a Chronic Management Program under which you
can also take OPD visits related to these conditions. What will be the limit on the number of OPDs,
for which condition, the details of that information are also
given in the last section of the policy worldings where But in different annexures,
information about the number of OPD visits has been given by mentioning different conditions and that too, you
can check it from the policy wordings document. Now the next hand on comes Cancer Booster Cover and Cancer Booster Cover
says that we will cover two expenses and extras related to cancer treatment which
you can cover with your sum insured but if you have taken Cancer Booster cover,
then these two expenses will be covered. Only related to Cancer Treatment We will cover additionally
What are these two expenses? First is Pre and Post Hospitalization
Expenses related to any medical condition. If you have taken any cancer related treatment
then you can use Cancer Booster cover to claim its pre and post expenses.
And second coverage is Day Care Treatment up to sum insured
. Up to whatever sum insured you choose. You can take day care treatment i.e.
treatment is taken at home, if any cancer treatment is done, then you can also cover it
and both these benefits will be given to you in the form of reimbursement claim. These are
pre and post, there is reimbursement as soon as it is received and apart from this, if you take any treatment as home care treatment,
then you will have to file reimbursement claim under this policy.
Next add on is Compassionate Visit in this. If any of your immediate family
members is away from you and gets hospitalized due to a life threatening condition
and no immediate family member is with them, then a maximum of ₹ 50,000
can be claimed for the two-way travel of any one immediate family member.
The condition is one that life threatening hospitalization
should be for more than 10 days. Only then can you claim this add on of Compassionate Visit.
The next add on comes that of Second Medical Opinion. Once any
medical condition has been diagnosed by a doctor, if the course holder wishes then
for his/her safety, he/she can also take a second medical opinion for confirmation and that too
for the listed medical conditions which are currently visible to you on the screen. If
any of these conditions are diagnosed then only you can use this add on. And the final add on is
Annual Screening for Cancer Diagnosed Patients. Policy holders who have been diagnosed with cancer
can use ₹ 10,000 every year towards getting tested
if they add this add on to their policy. Before we
look at the pricing of Aditya Birla Active One Max Plan, let us also understand the waiting period.
However, the waiting period is already mentioned in the add ons. The waiting
period here for PED is 36 months which you can reduce.
The waiting period is of specific days. The initial waiting period is of 24 months. The same is of 30 days.
Apart from this, there is some survival period and the waiting period for any test and medical condition.
I have explained it to you along with the features and benefits. However,
when you go online, When you purchase the policy,
the add ons for reducing the waiting period for specific disease and pet disease are not visible to you there because
you can get these options directly by talking to the insurance company. It
is also possible that when I checked the pricing, I did not mention any PED in it, so
maybe that is why those options are not visible. So let us once
understand what is the basic pricing of this plan. So that you can know that we will get these coverage and benefits
but is this plan also affordable or not? Here,
the standard family that I have taken for pricing is of two children and two adults,
the age of the adults is 40 and 36 years and among the children, the eldest son is of
the age of 15 years and the younger daughter is of the age of 10 years and their address is Delhi.
The sum insured here I have taken is ₹ 15 lakh, so let's see
how much will be its annual premium for Max variant aitya Bla Activ Max variant,
if we take it, the annual premium for this family will be
₹ 3576. If we add an extra add on in it, the medical equipment cover,
then this premium becomes
₹ 38384 i.e. Max Plus, if you take the variant, then that must be around ₹ 39 more.
₹ 40 for ₹ 15 lakh off coverage and the Max variant which is without medical
equipment cover and without advanced health checkups that will be around
₹ 35,700 These prices have been taken from the website of the insurance company and these prices
are currently the prices on the day this video is published, there
may be some revision in them later. If we talk about add ons, then some add ons are of time.
At the same time, some add ons can also be reduced and some add ons can also be increased, but
at present, I have explained all the add ons that are available to you and
have also told you what is their use. Now, is Aditya Birla Health Insurance Company
a trusted company, can we trust it, so it is very important to know about the insurance company.
So, if we talk about the insurance company, then
on the basis of the data that is available, the matrix is ​​quite detailed. Favorable is the claim settlement ratio which is above 90% and which
is the incurred claim ratio which sees that the insurance company is profitable and
is also settling the claims, then
the incurred claim ratio of this company is above average among the stand alone health insurance companies and as you have seen the plan
is quite flexible and you get good features even within the standard plan
but if If you are looking at a plan in which you
need maternity coverage or want any other specific coverage, then those options are not available here, but
still any coverage deficiency of the standard plan can be removed through add ons.
You may also face some problems. The first thing regarding this plan
may be related to the pricing. It is possible that you are getting some other plan from some other company
at a very reasonable price, then you may find this plan a bit expensive
and especially if you Add ons are added inside it. Apart from this, if
you have any pre-existing disease or if you
want to take this plan for any policy holder, then you will have to consider the loadings also, they can also increase your premium.
Along with this, I would like to tell you one thing that
the topmost concern in the negative feedback related to Aditya Birla Health Insurance Company
is regarding their customer care, i.e. when you call the customer in the time of emergency. If you want to connect with care,
it takes a very long time to be able to talk to them. If any
emergency happens, no one would want you to have to wait for a long time or
not be able to talk to the insurance company. And if it is a medical emergency
, it can be a very troublesome thing. So by considering all these factors and
along with the rest of your research, you can take the decision of taking your plan.
Through this video, my aim was to tell you about this plan. Let me
explain each feature and benefit of this policy very transparently in simple language so that
before paying the money for the policy, you can understand what and what coverage you are
getting under this plan. If you have understood the information given about this plan and
you find this video valuable, then you can like the video to show your love and support
where this information is needed, i.e. if someone in your knowledge
wants to take this plan or someone wants to take reference from you. If you are talking about this company,
you can also share this video with them so that it is not only helpful to you but you
can also help someone else. About this plan, about the company, about any feature shown in the video. If you
want to give any suggestion about the videos or content coming on the channel or you have any query, then immediately
write your point in the comment section, I will definitely answer it. And if you have not subscribed the channel till now, then
definitely subscribe the channel because similar types of initiatives are there.
You will continue to get transparent and unbiased
videos in the future also. Now in today's video, we
also discussed the concerns about Aditya Birla Health Insurance Company, but if you
want to know in detail
about this health insurance company or any other health insurance company and how it performs, then you
can watch the report card series. I Harvinder Singh take your permission now, I will get your permission next.
In the video till then take care stay fit and stay healthy Jai Hind